# **Timothy Iloba**

ilobatimothy@gmail.com | +234 (0) 813 784 0526

- o <a href="https://github.com/iloba">https://github.com/iloba</a>
- o https://www.linkedin.com/in/timothy-iloba/
- o sney.netlify.app

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Mid-Level Full Stack engineer with Knowledge in Cyber security (Application Security) and 4 year's experience working with startup companies. I apply my problem-solving skills, Software engineering skills and Cyber security skills to deliver efficient, scalable, secured and maintainable software solutions.

#### **SKILLS**

- o PHP + Laravel 9,
- o Laravel Livewire
- Javascript
- React Js
- Tailwind CSS
- Bootstrap
- o Agile & Scrum

- o Test Driven Development
- Design Patterns
- Object Oriented Programming
- o Data Structures and Algorithms
- Application Security
- o Vulnerability Testing
- o CI/CD

- o SEO
- Domain DrivenDevelopment
- Risk Management & Assessment

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Full Stack Software Engineer (remote)**

Rooah, Dover, Delaware USA

October 2021-September 2022

- Worked with the software engineering team on Client's projects Like a digital marketplace, A create to earn platform and in-house projects like a social media posts scheduling tool, email marketing tool and more.
- o Improved client satisfaction rate by 10% through the application of Agile principles, satisfying them through early and continuous delivery.

#### **Full Stack Software Engineer (remote)**

Trenova Consulting, Lagos, Nigeria

February 2021–October 2021

- Built a pupil reading platform and integrated a comic book library to retain end user's curiosity and satisfaction.
- o Improved on the website's user interface to match with our end users (the pupils) wants.
- o Improved the app performance by optimizing queries and integrating through iterative changes and updates.
- Monitored and managed the platform for Six months after my contract with the company was over.

## Frontend Engineer, Educational services

IT Central, Kaduna, Nigeria

September 2019 – September 2020

- Worked on the user interface of a school results management system, improved design quality and user experience.
- Worked on the design of a Point of sale (POS) machine receipt.
- Worked on the user interface of a Printing business platform and improved website authenticity by revamping the user interface.

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science (BSc.) in Cyber Security

## **AWARDS**

- Most Punctual staff of the year 2021
- Employee of the month May 2022